Joel Oppenheimer Papers 1990.0056
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series II: Poetry, undated, 1953-1987
  - Subseries A: Individual Poems, undated
    - Spring ( New Hampshire Journal) (variant TSS, not titled), ca. 1984 (Box 13:972)
    - Spring and Some ( Names, Dates, and Places), ca. 1972-1978 (Box 13:973)
    - Spring Poem ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 13:974)
    - Spring Some Years This Year, ca. 1971-1980 (Box 13:975)
    - Stamped Paid ( On Occasion), ca. 1960-1970 (Box 13:976)
    - Statement to the Citizens ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 13:977)
    - Stone Used as a Pillow, a Sacred Pillar, 1953 (Box 13:978)
    - Story of a Rent Strike, ca. 1971-1980 (Box 13:979)
    - Studies in Arabia Deserta ( In Time) (includes variant TSS, "Travels in Arabia Deserta"), 1963-1964 (Box 13:980)
    - Suck Villanelle ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 13:981)
    - Sue's Birthday ( On Occasion), ca. 1971 (Box 13:982)
    - Suite: Paranoia, 1972-1976 (Box 13:983)
    - Summer ( Why Not), ca. 1983-1985 (Box 13:984)
    - Summer Hits Rte 9 ( New Hampshire Journal), ca. 1982-1984 (Box 13:985)
    - Summer Songs ( New Spaces), 1974-1983 (Box 13:986)
    - Sum Total ( On Occasion), 1971 (Box 13:987)
    - Sun Alone, 1953 (Box 13:988)
    - Sunday at High Noon ( On Occasion), 1960-1970 (Box 13:989)
    - Sunday Morning ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 13:990)
    - Sunday Poem ( The Woman Poems) (TSS not titled), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 13:991)
    - Surgeon in Spite of Himself ( In Time), ca. 1962-1968 (Box 13:992)
    - Sweet Blues, and Other Songs ( In Time), ca. 1962-1968 (Box 13:993)
    - Tail in Two Cities, ca. 1960-1962 (Box 14:994)
    - Talking ( New Spaces), 1974-1983 (Box 14:995)
    - Talking About Scott, Reaching for Kleenex, ca. 1956-1960 (Box 14:996)
    - Tango Poem I ( The Woman Poems) (TSS not titled), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 14:997)
    - Tango Poem II ( The Woman Poems) (TSS not titled), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 14:998)
    - Teacher, ca. 1982-1984 (Box 14:999)
    - Teachers ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 14:1000)
    - Ted Berrigan ( Collected Later Poems), 1983-1984 (Box 14:1001)
    - Terror Codder ( On Occasion), ca. 1958-1962 (Box 14:1002)
    - Text ("for some of my best friends"), 1962 (Box 14:1003)
    - Thanksgiving 1981 (Box 14:1004)
    - Thanksgiving Grace ( On Occasion), 1967 (Box 14:1005)
    - Thanksgiving Grace ( Names, Dates, and Places), ca. 1972-1976 (Box 14:1006)
    - Thanksgiving Grace, 1975 (Box 14:1007)
    - That Voice, ca. 1983-1984 (Box 14:1008)
    - These Days ( New Spaces), 1973 (Box 14:1009)
    - Third Baseball Poem ( The Wrong Season), ca. 1972 (Box 14:1010)
    - Thirty Days, Next Case ( In Time), ca. 1962-1968 (Box 14:1011)
    - This is Stop Time ( On Occasion), 1960-1970 (Box 14:1012)
    - This Was Some Sort of Haiku ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 14:1013)
    - Those Old Men (Fragile/ Stained), ca. 1958-1962 (Box 14:1014)
    - Thick as Thieves, ca. 1956-1960 (Box 14:1015)
    - Thoughts of the Fat Man's Father ( Why Not) (includes variant TSS), ca. 1983-1984 (Box 14:1016)
    - Three and a Half Minute Mile ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 14:1017)
    - Three for Sam Greenberg ( In Time) (includes variant TSS, "Three Hospital Poems"), 1962-1968 (Box 14:1018)
    - Three Old Ladies ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 14:1019)
    - Tide, ca. 1953-1959 (Box 14:1020)
    - Time Out, ca. 1973-1980 (Box 14:1021)
    - Timesense ( On Occasion), ca. 1958-1962 (Box 14:1022)
    - Title Repeats ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 14:1023)
    - To a Friend ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 14:1024)
    - Today a Bathsheba, ca. 1953 (Box 14:1025)
    - Torn Nightgown ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 14:1026)
    - To See, ca. 1973-1980 (Box 14:1027)
    - To See the World as the World Is, ca. 1964? (Box 14:1028)
    - To the Congress, ca. 1972-1976 (Box 14:1029)
    - Touch Poem ( The Woman Poems) (variant TSS, not titled), 1973-1975 (Box 14:1030)
    - Transcendental Experience, ca. 1971-1980 (Box 14:1031)
    - Trapping, ca. 1958-1960 (Box 14:1032)
    - Traveling Poem ( The Woman Poems) (TSS not titled), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 14:1033)
    - Treatise ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 14:1034)
    - Triplets ( The Love Bit), 1957 (Box 14:1035)
    - Truck Farmer ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 14:1036)
    - Trunk ( On Occasion), 1971 (Box 14:1037)
    - Truth, ca. 1958-1962 (Box 14:1038)
    - Turning, ca.1956-1960 (Box 14:1039)
    - Two Baseball Poems ( The Wrong Season), ca. 1972 (Box 14:1040)
    - Two Deaths ("david stern, r f k, 6 june 1968) ( On Occasion) (Box 14:1041)
    - Two Haiku to Be Read Either One First ( Why Not), ca. 1983-1985 (Box 14:1042)
    - Two Headed Coin, ca. 1960-1970 (Box 14:1043)
    - Two Portraits All Ways, ca. 1972-1976 (Box 14:1044)
    - Undefined Tenderness ( The Love Bit), 1957 (Box 14:1045)
    - Untitled ( On Occasion), ca. 1966-1971 (Box 14:1046)
    - Valentine ( On Occasion), ca. 1966-1971 (Box 14:1047)
    - Valentine ( Names, Dates, and Places), 1975 (Box 14:1048)
    - Valentine, 1984 (Box 14:1049)
    - Valentine's Day 1974 ( Names, Dates, and Places) (Box 14:1050)
    - Valentine's Day 1975 (Box 14:1051)
    - Venz L'amors Mas Sol Mezeis, ca. 1958-1966 (Box 14:1052)
    - Verities ( On Occasion), ca. 1968-1971 (Box 14:1053)
    - Victorian Hakku ( On Occasion), 1960-1970 (Box 14:1054)
    - View, ca. 1960-1966 (Box 14:1055)
    - Village Poem ( New Spaces), ca. 1975-1980 (Box 14:1056)
    - Virtue (incomplete - second page missing?), ca. 1960-1970 (Box 14:1057)
    - Vowels ( Names, Dates, and Places), ca. 1972-1978 (Box 14:1058)
    - Waking in a Bed By a Ringing Telephone ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 14:1059)
    - Walk in the Country, ca. 1973-1980 (Box 14:1060)
    - Water Poem ( The Woman Poems) (TSS not titled), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 14:1061)
    - Way it is ( On Occasion), ca. 1958-1962 (Box 14:1062)
    - Way we Were ( New Spaces), 1978 (Box 14:1063)
    - Weaving Poem ( The Woman Poems), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 14:1064)
    - Wedding ("8 december 1968 tom and joan clancy") ( On Occasion) (Box 14:1065)
    - Wedding ("diane and nyles"), 1976 (Box 14:1066)
    - Wedding ("for dick and Alison burchell") ( On Occasion), 1969 (Box 14:1067)
    - Wedding ("for gordon and sue, 29 december 1969" ( On Occasion) (Box 14:1068)
    - Wedding ("for phillip and judy, 27 june 1970) ( On Occasion) (Box 14:1069)
    - Wedding ("for nick and sharifa"), 1977 (Box 14:1070)
    - Wedding ("under the spring moon"), 1980 (Box 14:1071)
    - Wedding Gifts ( Collected Later Poems), 1984 (Box 14:1072)
    - We Mark the Centennial of William Carlos Williams' Birth Observing a New Hampshire Patriot ( New Hampshire Journal) (variant TSS with variant titles), ca. 1983-1984 (Box 14:1073)
    - Wet Leaves, 1961 (Box 14:1074)
    - What Ought to Be a Psalm, 1957 (Box 14:1075)
    - What the ( On Occasion), 1960? (Box 14:1076)
    - When the Drums Stopped ( In Time), 1959-1962 (Box 14:1077)
    - When What You Dream ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 14:1078)
    - White Hope ( In Time), 1965 (Box 14:1079)
    - Will He Nill He, ca. 1960-1964 (Box 14:1080)
    - Wind Changes, 1964 (Box 14:1081)
    - Window, The Window (2) ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 14:1082)
    - Woman Joys, ca. 1962-1970 (Box 14:1083)
    - Word ( Why Not), ca. 1983-1985 (Box 14:1084)
    - Wrenching Out, ca. 1960-1966 (Box 14:1085)
    - Your Serve, ca. 1958-1962 (Box 14:1086)
    - Yellow Crone ( Names, Dates, and Places), ca. 1972-1978 (Box 14:1087)
    - Yesterday ( In Time), 1964 (Box 14:1088)
    - Young Bloods ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 14:1089)
    - Young Lovers ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 14:1090)
    - Young Mother Blues ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 14:1091)
    - Your Tits Poem ( The Woman Poems), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 14:1092)
    - Zeus, in May, Reflects on a Recent Letter from Astarte ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 14:1093)
    - Zoom Lens ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 14:1094)
    - Zoo Story ( In Time) (includes variant TSS, untitled), 1962-1968 (Box 14:1095)
    - Unidentified/ Untitled Poetry TSS (I), ca. 1957-1964 (Box 14:1096)
    - Unidentified/ Untitled Poetry TSS (II), ca. 1957-1964 (Box 14:1097)
    - Unidentified/ Untitled Poetry TSS (III), ca. 1957-1964 (Box 14:1098)
    - Unidentified/ Untitled Poetry TSS (IV), ca. 1975-1980 (Box 14:1099)
    - Unidentified/ Untitled Poetry TSS (V), ca. 1975-1983 (Box 14:1100)
    - Unidentified/ Untitled Poetry TSS (VI), ca. 1975-1985 (Box 14:1101)
    - Untitled Poem - long rant against America (style similar to Ginsberg?), ca. 1963? (Box 14:1102)
    - Untitled Poem in style of William Carlos Williams, ca. 1960 (Box 14:1103)
    - Untitled "Confessional" Poems, ca. 1962-1964 (Box 14:1104)
    - Untitled poems in MSS, ca. 1960 (Box 14:1105)
    - Untitled poem in MSS ("The candles all have red tips"), ca. 1957-1064 (Box 14:1106)
    - Untitled poems in MSS, 1975-1985 (Box 14:1107)
    - Untitled poems in MSS (includes poem dated 9/18/88-possibly JO's last poem), 1983-1988 (Box 14:1108)
  - Subseries B: Supporting materials (proofs, galleys, notes, etc.), undated, ca. 1947-1988
    - Loose-Leaf for Literary Largess (Juvenalia) (JO's earliest poetry, unpublished), ca. 1947-1951 (Box 14:1109)
    - Poetry TSS - Translations from French and Greek, ca. 1956-1962 (Box 14:1110)
    - Unidentified Song Lyrics in TSS and MSS, ca. 1959-1966 (Box 14:1111)
    - Song Lyrics by JO in TSS (some MSS), ca. 1960-1964 (Box 14:1112)
    - Poems by JO in The Nation - "April Fool", "Orpheus", 1959, 1962 (Box 14:1113)
    - Bound TSS of The Dutiful Son and The Love Bit, ca. 1961? (Box 14:1114)
    - Review of The Dutiful Son by Robert Creeley (printed in New Mexico Quarterly xxvii), ca. 1955-1957 (Box 14:1115)
    - The Love Bit - TSS typesetting copy, galleys w/ corrections, ca. 1962 (Box 14:1116)
    - TSS - Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers, ca. 1962? (Box 14:1117)
    - Bound TSS - Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers, ca. 1962 (Box 14:1118)
    - TSS of Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers (w/ typesetting notes), 1962, 1980 (Box 14:1119)
    - TSS of poems, "The Night Air Becomes Noisome", "Zoo Story", "Come on Baby", "The Three Old Ladies", bound to 1 pc. correspondence (editor of The Bridge?), 1964 (Box 14:1120)
    - Bound TSS (copy) In Time (different pagination from published version), ca. 1967-1968 (Box 14:1121)
    - In Time - photocopies of preliminary versions (as submitted to Sterling Lord Agency), ca. 1966? (Box 14:1122)
    - In Time - photocopy of TSS, includes several poems later published in On Occasion, ca. 1968 (Box 15:1123)
    - In Time - TSS with typesetting notes, ca. 1969 (Box 15:1124)
    - In Time - Galleys, ca. 1969 (Box 15:1125)
    - In Time - confirmation page proofs, ca. 1969 (Box 15:1126)
    - In Time - Partial proofs and jacket proof, ca. 1969 (Box 15:1127)
    - In Time - clippings of reviews, 1969-1970 (Box 15:1128)
    - On Occasion - early version 20 poem TSS, ca. 1968-1969 (Box 15:1129)
    - On Occasion - bound TSS with corrections, does not reflect final arrangement of poems, ca. 1971 (Box 15:1130)
    - On Occasion - bound TSS with hand corrections and printing notes, poems in final arrangement, ca. 1971 (Box 15:1131)
    - On Occasion - photocopy TSS, ca. 1971 (Box 15:1132)
    - On Occasion - photocopy TSS, includes dust jacket proof, ca. 1971 (Box 15:1133)
    - On Occasion - Jacket proofs, ad clipping, 1 pc. correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 15:1134)
    - Collection of TSS Poems with note "To Mulch, Jan. '72" includes "Spring Poem", "N.B.", " Peire Vidal at Thirty-Two", "A Long Testament", 1972 (Box 15:1135)
    - The Woman Poems - original TSS with printer's notes, 1975 (Box 15:1136)
    - The Woman Poems - copy of TSS, some hand corrections (includes "return" note from William Morris Agency), 1975 (Box 15:1137)
    - The Woman Poems - copy of TSS (some poems marked with gold star stickers), ca. 1975 (Box 15:1138)
    - The Woman Poems - preliminary dust jacket proofs, 1975 (Box 15:1139)
    - The Woman Poems - publicity materials, copies of reviews and ads, correspondence from Bobbs-Merrill, 1975 (Box 15:1140)
    - The Woman Poems - publicity note, including JO's mailing list and copies of review solicitations, 1975 (Box 15:1141)
    - The Woman Poems - related correspondence, including reviews from Muriel Rukeyser, Philip Whalen, Anne Waldman, and others, 1975 (Box 15:1142)
    - The Woman Poems - correspondence between JO and Allen Ginsberg, Diane DiPrima, Robert Creeley, ca. 1975 (Box 15:1143)
    - TSS sequence - "Meditations", "Camille Young, Camille Older", "Service Notice", "Celebrating the Peace", "The Man Discovered Through the Kitchen Window", ca. 1975-1978 (Box 15:1144)
    - Names, Dates, and Places - TSS, 1978 (Box 15:1145)
    - Names, Dates, and Places - copy of proof set, cover proofs, 1 pc. correspondence, 1978 (Box 15:1146)
    - "Poem for the New Year" - copy of Village Voice clipping, 1978 (Box 15:1147)
    - "On the Giving of the Tallis" - folded card (printer's sample?) (identical poem to "Ritual" in Generations), 1979 (Box 15:1148)
    - At Fifty - two pages preliminary notes, ca. 1980 (Box 17:1149)
    - At Fifty - poems not organized, numbering different from published version, ca. 1980 (Box 17:1150)
    - At Fifty - partial TSS, ca. 1980 (Box 17:1151)
    - At Fifty - TSS, 1980 (Box 17:1152)
    - At Fifty - copy of TSS, 1982 (Box 17:1153)
    - "Two from At Fifty" - proofs of mailer/flyer with envelope and 1 pc. correspondence, 1982 (Box 17:1154)
    - TSS of poems about the death of John Lennon - "For Sean Lennon" by JO, "For John Lennon" by Nat Oppenheimer, "The Songwriter" by Lem Oppenheimer, 1980 (Box 17:1155)
    - "Five Attempts at the Armenian" - includes "The Owl", "Give Me My Eyes", "Target Shooting", "We Were Walking", "For Hazmik", ca. 1980 (Box 17:1156)
    - Del Quien Lo Tomo - TSS suite includes "Adornment of Body Poem", "Jane Street Poem", "Autumn", ca. 1975 (Box 17:1157)
    - Del Quien Lo Tomo - proofs, correspondence from Walter Hamady, 1982 (Box 17:1158)
    - New Hampshire Journal - TSS, includes variant TSS, 1982 (Box 17:1159)
    - Notes Toward a Definition of David - TSS with author's proof and 2 pcs. printing correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 17:1160)
    - 4 sets TSS packet including "Houses", "The Charm", and "Cacti" (all poems appeared in New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 17:1161)
    - New Spaces - original TSS, arranged, with working title "Drawing from Life", ca. 1983-1985 (Box 17:1162)
    - New Spaces - TSS (2 sets), ca. 1983-1985 (Box 17:1163)
    - New Spaces - Publicity, reviews, promotional materials, 1985 (Box 17:1164)
    - Why Not - TSS, set of corrected galleys, 1985 (Box 17:1165)
    - Why Not - page proofs, TSS of preface, correspondence with David Lorczak (printer), 1983-1985 (Box 17:1166)
    - Why Not - review by Don Wellman (including Hayden Carruth and Jonathan Williams), ca. 1987 (Box 17:1167)
    - Generations - early TSS, includes "Oldest", "What My Father Said", "Child", "Mother", "Son", ca. 1980-1983 (Box 17:1168)
    - Generations - TSS ("Bob's Slow Foods Edition 4 of 5") includes correspondence between JO and publisher regarding galleys, 1984 (Box 17:1169)
    - Generations - galleys, correspondence, 1986 (Box 17:1170)
    - "The Poetry of Porking" - proofs of Maledicta article includes 1 pc. correspondence from Reinhold Aman (Variant poem title - "Greens"), 1985 (Box 17:1171)
    - "Ger" - as printed in The New Hampshire Home Defender, 1986 (Box 17:1172)
    - The Uses of Adversity - TSS drafts, ca. 1986 (Box 17:1173)
    - The Uses of Adversity - reviews and correspondence, 1987 (Box 17:1174)
    - Names and Local Habitations - production materials, correspondence, TSS of Accolade and Introduction, draft of index, partial proofs (copy), 1988 (Box 17:1175)
    - Names and Local Habitations - copies of The Dutiful Son and The Love Bit, 1988 (Box 17:1176)
    - Names and Local Habitations - copies from In Time, 1988 (Box 17:1177)
    - Names and Local Habitations - copies from Just Friends/Friends and Lovers, and On Occasion, 1988 (Box 17:1178)
    - Names and Local Habitations - copies of "Baseball" poems ( The Wrong Season) and The Woman Poems, 1988 (Box 17:1179)
    - "Active Folders" at time of JO's death
      - New Hampshire Poems - TSS of "Charms", "We Mark the Centennial...", "In New Hampshire", "Country Alba", "Summer Hits Route 9", "A New Hampshire Journal", "Discovery", "Spring", "Credo", "Autumn", "Evening", and "Gryllidae Achene", ca. 1987 (Box 17:1180)
      - Collections - TSS of "Five Attempts at the Armenian", "Generations", "Greens", ca. 1983-1985 (Box 17:1181)
      - Occasions - see inside folder for poem listing, most poems published in Collected Later Poems, 1983-1987 (Box 17:1182)
      - Straight - see inside folder for poem listing, most poems published in Collected Later Poems, 1983-1987 (Box 17:1183)
      - News Poems - TSS of "Paean, Prematurely...", "Granite", "Hurricane", "Elephant Blues", "For Hoyt Wilhelm", "For Halley's Comet", "The News", "The Foster Mother", ca. 1985-1987 (Box 17:1184)
      - To Work -- "Long Blues", "Grace" (MSS), "Slam Stewart" (MSS), "Dull Burnt" (MSS), "To Hear", "Toker Looks Like a Pig", "Plates (from Fenollosa)", ca. 1982-1985 (Box 17:1185)
- Series III: Prose, undated, 1947-1988
  - Early Prose and Political Writings, 1960-1968
    - "And the World Shall Yield Forth Food", ca. 1960? (Box 17:1186)
    - "Guerilla Warfare", "War and Western Man" - fragments of political writings, includes flyer for political lecture given by JO, ca. 1962 (Box 17:1187)
    - "Fair Play for Cuba Committee" - TSS fact sheets (not clear that author is JO), ca. 1962? (Box 17:1188)
    - Clippings related to Guerilla Warfare, 1961-1962 (Box 17:1189)
    - Short Prose Fragments in TSS, ca. 1962? (Box 17:1190)
    - Short Prose Pieces in TSS, ca. 1968 (Box 17:1191)
  - Drama and Film Projects
    - The Great American Desert - TSS marked "1st draft - variant", ca. 1960 (Box 17:1192)
    - The Great American Desert - variant TSS versions, outline notes, theater programs, reviews, 1961, 1970 (Box 17:1193)
    - The Great American Desert - TSS, ca. 1961-1966 (Box 17:1194)
    - The Great American Desert - TSS photocopy and TSS carbon, ca. 1961-1966 (Box 17:1195)
    - Flyer for "The Last of the Bummers" - freeform project by Theatre Genesis, inspired by The Great American Desert, ca. 1964-1969 (Box 17:1196)
    - The Great American Desert - copies of publication in The Off Off Broadway Book, 1972 (Box 17:1197)
    - The Great American Desert - William Morris Agency contract regarding performance in San Jose, CA, 1975 (Box 17:1198)
    - The Great American Desert - copy of play with notes, program for Westbeth 10th anniversary party, 1980 (Box 17:1199)
    - Miss Right - TSS of play with song lyrics by JO, flyers, copy of Village Voice review, ca. 1963 (Box 17:1200)
    - Miss Right - copy of TSS with one piece correspondence from George Butterick, ca. 1963, 1980 (Box 17:1201)
    - Like a Hill - TSS, ca. 1966 (Box 17:1202)
    - Like a Hill - program (The Loft on 54th Street), ca. 1966 (Box 17:1203)
    - Drama fragments in TSS - "Two Worms in the Apple", "An Interview", "Show-down in the South Forty", ca. 1960-1965 (Box 17:1204)
    - Drama Fragments - not identified, undated (Box 17:1205)
    - Drama TSS - not identified (Cupid, Pan, Sam, Ruth), undated (Box 17:1206)
    - The Perfect Detonator - TSS photocopy (copy 1), ca. 1968? (Box 17:1207)
    - The Perfect Detonator - TSS photocopy (copy 2), ca. 1968? (Box 17:1208)
    - The Perfect Detonator - TSS photocopy (copy 3), ca. 1968? (Box 17:1209)
    - The Perfect Detonator - TSS, with one piece correspondence from Gloria Steinem, ca. 1968? (Box 17:1210)
    - "The Oyster and the Wind" - film treatment (with MSS Corrections) (2 sets), ca. 1968-1972? (Box 17:1211)
    - "Grass Land" - treatment and early draft of screenplay, ca. 1969? (Box 17:1212)
    - Undeveloped plays and screenplays, ca. 1970 (Box 17:1213)
  - Short Stories and Non-Fiction Book Projects
    - Last Call - TSS Drafts and contracts (unfinished/unpublished novel), ca. 1969 (Box 17:1214)
    - The Wrong Season - News clippings about the NY Mets, 1971-1972 (Box 17:1215)
    - The Wrong Season - TSS fragments not yet organized, ca. 1972 (Box 17:1216)
    - The Wrong Season - Bound TSS, ca. 1972-1973 (Box 18:1217)
    - The Wrong Season - Bound TSS (Clean/ revised copy), ca. 1972-1973 (Box 18:1218)
    - The Wrong Season - TSS of introduction by Joe Flaherty, notes and ephemera, including baseball programs, 1972 (Box 18:1219)
    - The Wrong Season - cover proofs, reviews, notes, and promotional materials, 1973 (Box 18:1220)
    - TSS copy of short stories "I Could Marry Her", and "Friday Night was Always a Ball", ca. 1966? (Box 18:1221)
    - TSS of short story "Re-entry", ca. 1975 (Box 18:1222)
    - Pan's Eyes - TSS of stories, some variant TSS, ca. 1966-1970? (Box 18:1223)
    - Pan's Eyes - TSS of stories, ca. 1966-1970? (Box 18:1224)
    - Pan's Eyes - TSS copy of stories, ca. 1966-1970 (Box 18:1225)
    - Pan's Eyes - 2 copies of contract, 1 pc. correspondence, 1976 (Box 18:1226)
    - TSS Proposal for The Single Father's Cookbook (not produced), 1077-1979 (Box 18:1227)
    - TSS of children's book (not produced) with 1 pc. correspondence, 1976 (Box 18:1228)
    - TSS of children's books The Friends and How Big Was Lemuel? (neither produced), ca. 1975-1979 (Box 18:1229)
    - "Drying Out" - autobiographical essay (unfinished book?), 1977 (Box 18:1230)
    - TSS of pornographic short stories (never published?), ca. 1970-1980? (Box 18:1231)
    - TSS copies of pornographic stories, ca. 1970-1980? (Box 18:1232)
    - Marilyn Lives - TSS with corrections, ca. 1980 (Box 18:1233)
    - Marilyn Lives - Publicity Photo of JO and two copies of publisher's press release, 1981 (Box 18:1234)
    - TSS Book on Fatherhood (not published), 1982 (Box 18:1235)
    - Submission by JO for humor book, Bred Any Good Rooks Lately? (never published?), 1986 (Box 18:1236)
  - Non-Fiction Articles
    - Copies, clippings of publications by JO (some Village Voice, also a letter to New York Magazine, also reviews for The World), 1969-1970 (Box 18:1237)
    - TSS carbons of Village Voice columns, ca. 1970-1972 (Box 18:1238)
    - TSS Articles by JO (mostly Village Voice) (some not published), ca. 1970-1972? (Box 18:1239)
    - Copies of articles and reviews in Newsday and Book World, 1971-1973 (Box 18:1240)
    - Copies of Village Voice articles (some poetry publications), 1972-1973 (Box 18:1241)
    - TSS carbons of Village Voice columns (includes TSS of poems published in VV), 1972-1973 (Box 18:1242)
    - Copies of Village Voice columns/ Publications, 1974 (Box 18:1243)
    - TSS carbons of Village Voice columns, 1974 (Box 19:1244)
    - TSS carbons of Village Voice columns, 1975 (Box 19:1245)
    - TSS of unfinished, unpublished Village Voice columns, 1975 (Box 19:1246)
    - TSS Review of Lost and Found by John Nonce, with one piece correspondence, clipping of published version, 1975 (Box 19:1247)
    - TSS carbons of Village Voice columns (includes 1 pc. editorial correspondence), 1976 (Box 19:1248)
    - Village Voice Ephemera - Publicity materials and research notes, 1976 (Box 19:1249)
    - TSS carbons of Village Voice columns, 1976-1977 (Box 19:1250)
    - Copies of Village Voice articles, 1976-1978 (Box 19:1251)
    - Book Reviews by JO (some for New York Times), ca. 1976-1980 (Box 19:1252)
    - Columns by JO (some Village Voice?), ca. 1976-1980 (Box 19:1253)
    - TSS carbons of Village Voice columns, ca. 1978 (Box 19:1254)
    - TSS carbons of Village Voice columns, 1979 (Box 19:1255)
    - TSS carbons of undated articles (some Village Voice?), ca. 1975-1979 (Box 19:1256)